Felipe de Moraes Modesto

CAREER SUMARY

I have been working as a Software Developer in the Game Industry since 2011. During my career I have implemented games and business applications for multiple platforms. For the past 4 years I have also taken the role of Creative Director, coordinating programmers and designer teams to ensure asset quality and compliance to project scope. I also have experience managing clients and have worked with Brazil's biggest corporate clients. I currently reside in and am a permanent resident of Canada.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• 2011-2018 - Game Developer & Creative Director - Fira Soft Ltd.

Programmer & Production Lead (2011-2014) Programmer & Creative Director (2014-2018)

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming

C++, C#, Python, Lua, Java, JavaScript, R, Linux Shell, SQL

Technologies

Unity3D, Mobile Development, Corona SDK, Android Studio, MS Visual Studio IceScrum, SQlite, Google Analytics, rStudio, ADB, OBS

Process

Scrum (IceScrum), Git/Mercurial (GitHub / Bitbucket / Gitlab), GDD, TDD

Graphic Design

Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Audition, After Effects, Premiere)

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

SEVeN - ICN Distributed Network Communication Simulator - OMNet++

C++ Roles: Architecture model, protocol stack implementation and debugging, Python data analysis, production of technical reports & other academic material

- Kriophobia (In Development) Survival Horror PC / PS4 Unity3D
- C# Roles: Feature programming, project management, production validation, asset validation, design documentation production, debugging
- NeuroVR In-surgery Cognitive Evaluation Tool PC / SteamVR Unity3D
- C# Roles: Project management, client interaction, feature programming, debugging, interface/usability design, patient evaluation metric design
- Jimmy Five Brick-Breaker Brick Breaker iOS / Android Unity3D
- C# Roles: Project management, feature programming, project-specific tool implementation, game design, art asset conformity management (client requirement)
- Move-it! Charades Virtual Board-Game iOS / Android Corona SDK

Lua Roles: Lead designer and programmer, core feature implementation, UI/UX design, SOL publishing and maintaining store presence, game content production, client support

Other Custom Mobile-centric Projects for Clients - Unity, Corona, Android

Lua Roles: Varied roles associated with the positions of creative director and programmer, C# feature implementation, client management, production management, game design, Java documentation production

Multiple papers published in Academic Conferences and Journals

LaTeX Roles: Academic research proposal, implementation, analysis and document production Python Plase access google scholar page for a mostly complete list of publications

EDUCATION

- 2014-2018 PhD in Computer Science University of Ottawa
- 2011-2014 Master of Computer Science University of Brasilia (Brazil)
- 2007-2011 Bachelor in Computer Science University of Brasilia (Brazil)

CONTACT

- @ felipe@modesto.io
- +1 613 883 2898
- Ottawa ON, Canada
- in /femodesto

Career Interests

- **◆ Software Developer**
- Game Developer
- Programmer
- ◆ Production Lead

BIO

Master of Computer Science

Language Skills

English
Portuguese
French
Spanish

Interests

- Data Analysis
- Automation
- Networks
- Graphics
- Innovation

Personal Interests

- Board-games
- Photography
- Mech. Keyboards
- Plotting Graphs
- Curious Facts

Personal Traits

- Team Player
- Leadership
- Problem-Solver
- Multi-tasker
- Perfectionist

SOCIAL MEDIA

github: felipemodesto twitter: felipemodesto

More details available at:

www.modesto.io